Benjamin Franklin Papers Part 5 -- Letters to Franklin 1779 December-1780 December Mss.B.F85inventory05
American Philosophical Society
- Letters to Benjamin Franklin.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1780; L. 2p.; -------, -------. Dresden
    Sends German translation of Franklin's works. Wishes to know the titles of any other work written by him in order to have them added to these three volumes. The quarto book is from H: H. the Prince of Furstenberg, who has brought together here into a philosophical and historical society some learned men of this captial.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, [1780.]; L. 1p.; ------, --------
    Warning him against entrusting the affairs of M. Chaffert to De Baumont. Says the latter is a swindler and has been in prison several times. The Public Prosecutor of the Chatelet district could tell all about him.
    A.E. "Anonymous letter written with the left hand to avoid detection."
  - to Benjamin Franklin, [1780.]; A.L. 1p.; -------, ------
    Highway robbers took the few francs he had; asks Franklin's assistance.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, [1780.]; L. 1p.; ------, ------
    In reference to a package of letters written by a self-styled prophet and miracle-worker and addressed to Congress and Washington.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, [C. 1779 Aug.]; Verses 3p.; Verses, ------ ------
    On the war between France and England and the reverses sustained by the English fleets. Reflection on current events of the war by an old man of eighty.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, [1781 c. April 21]; A.L. 1p.; Intelligence from Bilbao
    Two American vessels having arrived at Bilbao, announce the capture, in Chesapeake Bay, of the "Romulus" by M. [Jean Le Gardeus] de Tilly, commander of "L'Eveille."
  - to Benjamin Franklin, N. 1p.; -----, ------
    Expects to dine with M. Turgot and Baron d'Helbach at Franklin's house on Friday.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, N. 1p.; -----, ------
    Requesting him to let M. Turgot know if the dinner will take place next day.